Register of the George Constantine Guins papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Speeches and Writings, 1918-1964
  - "Law Does Not Wither Away in the Soviet Union," Russian Review, printed copy, 1950 July (Reel 6)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 6: 20
  - "A Ray of Light in the Realm of Darkness," typescript, 1951 October 3 (Reel 6)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 6: 21
  - Soviet Law and Soviet Society, The Hague, typescript, 1954
    - Part I (Reel 6)
      Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 6: 22
    - Part II (Reel 7)
      Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 7: 1
      Includes review by V. A. Riasanovsky, undated.
  - "Tserkov' i voina" (date mailed), background notes and typescript, 1954 September 11 (Reel 7)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 7: 2
  - "Po povodu khirotonii Episkopa Aliaskinskogo," holograph, 1955 September 11 (?) (Reel 7)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 7: 3
  - "Helpless Mammy," Reader's Digest, typescript, 1955 November 7 (Reel 7)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 7: 4
  - "Amerika na pereput'i," typescript, 1964 December 1 (Reel 7)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 7: 5
  - "Nerazreshennye problemy 1964 goda," typescript, 1965 January 8 (Reel 7)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 7: 6
  - "Liudi vsekh ras obediniaites'," typescript, 1965 January 13 (Reel 7)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 7: 7
- Course Materials, 1918-1953
  Lecture notes, reading lists, examination questions, background material, rolls and syllabi, arranged chronologically by period and alphabetically by physical form and course title thereunder.
  - Omsk, "Lektsii po grazhdanskomu pravu," holograph, 1918-1919 (Reel 7)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 7: 8
  - Harbin, 1922-1941
    - Lectures
      - "Eticheskie osnovy prava," holograph, undated (Reel 7)
        Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 7: 9
      - "Khoziaistvennoe pravo," holograph, undated (Reel 7)
        Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 7: 10
      - "Pravo i religiia," holograph, undated (Reel 7)
        Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 7: 11
      - "Programma. Literatura po grazhdanskomu pravu," typescript and printed matter, undated (Reel 7)
        Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 7: 12
        Includes reading lists and lectures on special legal issues (tort law, absolute rights, property and family law) as well as articles on legal matters by Guins published earlier.
      - "Sistema kursa torgovogo prava," holograph, undated (Reel 7)
        Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 7: 13
      - "Grazhdanskoe pravo," holograph, 1922 (Reel 8)
        Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 7: 14
      - "Pedagogicheskoe i motivatsionnoe deistvie prava," holograph, 1930 (Reel 8)
        Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 7: 15
    - Syllabi (programs)
      - "Programma po torgovomu pravu," typescript, undated (Reel 8)
        Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 7: 16
      - "Programmy prof. G. K. Ginsa po rimskomu pravu," Harbin Legal Faculty, printed copy, undated (Reel 8)
        Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 7: 17
      - "Programma po entsiklopedii prava (dlia studentov I kursa Kommercheskogo fakul'teta za I-oe polugodie uchebn. goda" [See: Oversize File], 1939 (Reel 9)
      - "Programma po entsiklopedii prava (dlia studentov I kursa Kommercheskogo fakul'teta za I-oe polugodie uchebn. goda," typescript, 1941 (Reel 8)
        Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 7: 18
      - "Programma po politicheskoi ekonomii (I-yi semestr) dlia studentov I-go kursa Kommercheskogo fak-ta S. M. Universiteta (v 1941 g.)," typescript, 1941 May (Reel 8)
        Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 7: 19
  - California, - University of California, Berkeley
    - Slavic 180A-180B, 181 (lectures on Russian and Soviet history and culture), 1947-1953 (Reel 8)
      Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 7: 20-21
      Includes background notes, research materials, literature summaries and reviews, examination questions, student rolls and related printed matter (pages torn from Russian calendars, book reviews and articles clipped from various newspapers and journals).
    - Slavic 180A-180B, 181 (lectures on Russian and Soviet history and culture), 1947-1953 (Reel 8)
      Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 8: 1
    - Political Science 116 (lectures on Russian and Soviet law) and Political Science 141 (lectures on Soviet Government), 1947-1953 (Reel 9)
      Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 8: 2-3
      Includes background notes, research materials, literature summaries and reviews, examination questions, student rolls and related printed matter (pages torn from Russian calendars, book reviews and articles clipped from various newspapers and journals). Also includes The Challenge: Bulletin of the Association of Former Political Prisoners of Soviet Labor Camps, Vol. I, #1 (July 1950).
- Subject File, 1931-1953
  Appeals, by-laws, correspondence, notes, statutes, clippings and other printed matter, arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Materialism. Summary of a speech by N. O. Losskii, entitled "Ideal-realizm protiv materializma,", 1953 September 14 (Reel 9)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 9: 1
  - Mishpat Gaborrim. Statutes, by-laws, and correspondence relating to the establishment of the Jewish Arbitration Court "Mishpat Gaborrim" in Harbin, 1931-1932 (Reel 9)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 9: 2
    Includes list of judges.
  - Orthodox Church in America. Appeals to Ninth and Tenth American Councils, undated (Reel 9)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 9: 3
    Includes letter from parishioners of St. John church in Berkeley to Rev. Nikolai Veiglas, additions and corrections to church by-laws (notes by Guins).
  - Tubabao, Philippines. Appeal to Senator William F. Knowland, asking for expedited immigration for Russians on Tubabao, 1949 July (Reel 9)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 9: 4
  - Miscellany. Information items and reports on situation in China and St. John Russian Orthodox Church in Berkeley, CA, undated (Reel 9)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 9: 5
- Oversize File, 1964 and undated
  Address honoring Guins, certificate of service, and course materials.
  - Address, honoring Guins for his service with the Chinese Eastern Railway, undated (Reel 9)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 10: 1
  - Certificate of Service, United States Information Agency, 1964 July 21 (Reel 9)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 10: 2
  - Course materials - Harbin - Syllabi (Programs). "Programma po entsiklopedii prava (dlia studentov I kursa Kommercheskogo fakul'teta za I-oe polugodie uchebn. goda,", 1939 (Reel 9)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 10: 3